Guide to the Rice University Information Files, 1910-2019 UA 361
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
- Series VIII: H
  - Huddle, Donald L.
  - Hudspeth, C.M. (Hank)
  - Huff House
    See also: [Ralph S.] O'Connor House
  - Huffler, Lynne
  - Hughes, A.L.
  - Hughes, Howard
  - Hugh O'Brien Youth Foundation/World Leadership Congress, August 1996
    See also: President's Office, Assistant to the President (Carl MacDowell) Box 158 [Restricted]
  - Hulet, Randall
  - Human Performance and Health Sciences Dept.
  - [Rice] Human Resources
  - Humanitarian Medical Outreach
  - Humanities Building
  - [Rice U.] Humanities, School of
  - Humanities Research Center
    See also: Center for the Study of Cultures
  - Humphrey, Herbert K.
  - Hurricanes and Aftermath
  - Hurricane Harvey, 2017
  - Hurricane Research Institute
  - Huston, J. Dennis
  - Huston, Priscilla J.
  - Hutchinson, John
  - Huxley, Julian S.
  - Huxley Symposium
  - Hyman, Ferne
  - Hyman, Harold
- Series IX: I
  - IBM
  - ICE
  - Ice Hockey, 1933/34 - 1939/40
  - The Idlers Club
  - Ikenberry, David L.
  - Illig, Carl
  - Imambekov, Adilet
  - Impact Rice Retreat
  - [Rice] Inflatable Dome
  - Information Systems
  - Information Technology (Services)
  - Ingersoll, Richard
  - Innovation District
  - Inscriptions (Rice walls, columns, statues)
  - Institute for Computer Services and Applications (ICSA)
  - Institute for Engineering Deans
  - Institute for Sustainable & Applied Infodynamics
  - Institute for the Arts, 1969-1972
  - Institute for the Arts, 1973-1979
  - Institute for the Arts, 1980 -
  - Institute for the Arts - Insurance
  - Institute for Urban Research
  - Institute of Biosciences and Bioengineering
  - Institute of International Education
  - Institute of Religion
  - Institute of Urban Planning
  - [Office of] Institutional Research
  - Integrated Waste Management Services
  - Integration
    See also: Students - Minorities
  - [Rice U.] Intensive English Program
  - Interclub Council
  - Intercourse (Architectural Department)
  - Interface Symposium
  - Internal Audit, Dept. of
  - International Conference in Fast Neutron Physics
  - International Conference on Low Temperature Physics and Chemistry
  - International Education
  - International Programs, Office of
  - International Scientific Symposium
  - [Office of] International Services of Rice Univ.
  - International Space University
  - [Office of] International Students and Scholars
  - Internet
  - Internet2
  - Intramural Council/Sports
  - [Rice] Investments
  - IRE and AIEE
  - Irwin, Keith
  - ISAR - Indian Students at Rice
  - Iskander, Maryana
  - Islamic Chair in Economics, Finance, and Management
  - Isle, Walter
  - Ivy, John Smith
- Series X: J
  - Jaber, Thomas
  - Jackson, Henry
  - Jackson, Roy
  - Jaco, W.H.
  - Jaffe, Amy Myers
  - Jalbert, Pierre
  - Jamail Plaza, Joe & Lee
  - James, Dean
  - James, Edmund
  - Janus
  - [Rice University] Japan Trip 1992
  - Javelin "Twins"
  - Jefferson Davis Association
  - Jelinkova, Klara
  - Jemison, Mae
  - Jenkins, Mark, MD
  - Jeopardy [TV game show]
  - Jernigan, Tamara
  - Jessen, Frank W.
  - Jewish Studies
  - Jews at Rice
  - Jiankui, He
  - John and Anne "Grove"
  - John, George
  - John, Patricia
  - Johnson, Dan
  - Johnson, Don H.
  - Johnson, Eric C.
  - Johnson, Francis Ellis
  - Johnson, Gaylord
  - Johnson, H.L.
  - Johnson, Lyndon B.
  - Johnson, Raymond
  - Johnson, Richard
  - Johnson Space Center
    See also: NASA; Lunar Science Institute
  - Johnson, Todd
  - Johnston, Mary Elizabeth
  - Joint Campus Ministries
  - Jones, Anita K.
  - Jones, Charlie F.
  - [Mary Gibbs] Jones College
  - Jones, Frank
  - [Jesse H.] Jones Graduate School - student association
  - [Jesse H.] Jones Graduate School of Administration/Management
  - Jones, Jesse H.
  - Jones Hall
  - Jones Hooter
  - Jones, Joseph E.
  - Jones, Mark
  - Jones, Mary Gibbs (Mrs. Jesse H.)
  - [Mary Gibbs] Jones Professorship in History
  - [Jesse H.] Jones Professorship in Management
  - Jones, Robert
  - Jones, Roy Glenn
  - Jones, Samuel
  - Jones, Sir Henry
  - Jordan, King of
  - Josey, Jack S.
  - Jost, John F.
  - Journal of Southern History
  - Journal of Young Investigators
  - Joyner, J. Scott
  - [Colloquium in] Judaic Studies
  - [Code of] Judicial Procedure
  - Jump, J. Robert
  - Junior Achievement Management Academy
  - Junior League
- Series XI: K
  - Kafafi, Zakya H.
  - Kahn, Louis I
  - Kahn, Lisa
  - Kahn, Robert
  - Kalb, Elizabeth
  - Kalb, Ervin ("Tiny")
  - Kalil, Susie
  - Kambhu, Pat
  - Kapiloff, Helen
  - Kaplan, Bert
  - Kapp, Robert A.
  - Karlgaard, Joe
  - Katz, Paul
  - Kavraki, Lydia
  - Keally, Francis
  - Kean, Melissa
  - Kecht, Regina
  - [W.M.] Keck Center for Computational Biology
  - [W.M.] Keck Center for Interdisciplinary Bioscience Training
  - [W.M.] Keck Foundation Professorship in Geophysics
  - Keck Hall
    See also: Chemistry Building and Laboratory
  - Keck, Howard B.
  - Keefe, Christina
  - Keeton, Darra
  - Kelber, Werner Heinz
  - Keller-McNulty, Sallie
  - Kelley, Mrs. Edward W. [Allie May Autry]
  - Kelley, Edward Watson, Jr.
  - Kelly, Hugh Rice
  - Kelly, Kevin
  - Kelty, Chris
  - Keneally, Catherine
  - Ken Kennedy Institute for Information Technology
    See also: Citi control folder
  - Kennedy, Edward M. "Ted"
  - Kennedy, John F.
  - Kennedy, Ken
  - [John F.] Kennedy Podium
  - Kennedy, Robert F., Jr.
  - Kennon, Paul
  - Kenny, Gale
  - Kermode, Sir Frank
  - Kerr, Baine
  - Kerry, John
  - Khabasheska, Valery
  - Khan, Kamran
  - Kiang, Ching-Hwa
  - Kiepper, Alan F.
  - Kieschnick, William F.
  - Killian, Thomas C.
  - Kim, Dae M.
  - Kimbro, Rachel T.
  - Kinder Institute for Urban Research
    See also: Urban Research Center
  - Kinesiology Dept.
  - King, Martin Luther, Jr. (Day at Rice)
  - King, W.O.
  - Kinsey, James L.
  - KIPP - Rice Scholars Corps
  - Kirby, Kevin
  - Kirk, Harris Elliott
  - Kirkland, William Alexander
  - Kirner, Juvanta
  - Kissinger, Henry
  - Kittredge, George L.
  - Kitts, Jimmy
  - Kiwanis Club
  - Klein, Anne
  - Klineberg, Stephen L.
  - Klinger, Ben
  - Knapp, Carl M.
  - Knightly, Edward
  - Knodel, Don
  - Knowledge: Initiative for Students
  - Kobayashi, Riki
  - Koch, Fred C.
  - Koehler, Richard
  - Koelbel, Charles
  - Kofoid, Charles A.
  - Kolenda, Konstantin
  - Kolomeisky, Anatoly
  - Konisky, Jordan
  - Konrad, Linn
  - Kotch, Mrs. M. Arthur (Clara Margaret Mohr)
  - Koushanfar, Farinaz
  - KOWL Radio
  - Kraft Hall for Social Sciences
  - Kramer, Tommy
  - Kranz, Gene
  - Kratzenstein, Klaus-Christhart
  - Krause, Kathie Scobee
  - Kresge Foundation
  - Kripal, Jeffrey
  - Krueger, Robert
  - Krzyzaniak, Marian
  - KTRU (3 Folders)
  - Ku Klux Klan
  - Kulkarni, V.S.
  - Kumari, Siva
  - Kurtzman, Jeffrey
  - Kyle Morrow Memorial Room
- Series XII: L
  - "La Ark Tex Alumnor"
  - Lacey, Neal T.
  - Lacrosse Club
  - Lacy, Bill N.
  - Lady Owl NEWS
  - Lamb, Sydney M.
  - Lamos, Colleen
  - Lancaster Hotel
  - Landscaping
    See also: Trees
  - Lane, A.C.
  - Lane, David
  - Lane, Mary Ellen
  - Lane, Neal F.
  - Lane, Sarah
  - Lane, William Homer
  - Language [Lab] Resource Center
  - Lanier Cynthia
  - Lankford, Robert
  - la Rose, Pierre de Chaignon
  - Larsen, Erik
  - Lassig, Oswald Joseph
  - Laughery, Kenneth R.
  - Laux Lila
  - Lavenda, Richard
  - LaVergne, Tommy
  - LaViolette, Adria
  - Law, Theodore N.
  - Law and History, Joint Degree in
  - Lawson, Rev. William A.
  - Lawton, Wayne
  - Leach, J. Sayles
  - Leadership Rice News
  - Lear, Floyd Seward
  - Leary, Dr. Timothy
  - Lecture: Protest 4-27-88
  - Lecture - Questionnaires
  - Lectures - Art History
  - Lectures - Bochner/Scientia Colloquia
  - Lectures - Brown Foundation J. Newton Rayzor Series
  - Lectures - Burkitt Foundation
  - Lectures - Campbell Series
  - Lectures- Centennial Series
  - Lectures - Center for Technology in Teaching and Learning
  - Lectures - [Harry and Hazel] Chavanne Series on Religion & Public Policy
  - Lectures - CITI
  - Lectures - College Series
  - Lectures - Dean's Series
  - Lectures - Department of History
  - Lectures - Departmental Misc.
  - Lectures - Departmental: School of Humanities
  - Lectures - Department of Space Physics/Astronomy
  - Lectures - Dugan Series
  - Lectures - Engineering Series
  - Lectures - Erwin Frederick Kalb Series
  - Lectures - Ethics, Politics and Society
  - Lectures - Fondren/Information Technology Series
  - Lectures - Friends of Fondren Library
  - Lectures - Gray/Wawro Lectures in Gender, Health and Well-being
  - Lectures - [Michael P.] Hammond Memorial Lectures
  - Lectures - History of Science Series
  - Lectures - Jewish Studies
  - Lectures - M.B. Porter Series
  - Lectures - Marlar Foundation, Series in Space Physics and Astronomy
  - Lectures - Menil/Rice Series
  - Lectures - Misc. (not in a series)
  - Lectures - [Oscar] Neuhaus Series
  - Lectures - Peterkin Series in Economics
  - Lectures - "Picasso's Decisions" Series
  - Lectures - President's Series: General, Lists, criteria
  - Lectures - President's Series 1960's
  - Lectures - President's Series 1970's
  - Lectures - President's Series 1980's
  - Lectures - President's Series 1990's
  - Lectures - President's Series 2000's
  - Lectures - President's Lectures Series of Diverse Scholars
  - Lectures - Provost's Series
  - Lectures - Public
  - Lectures - Rice Chapel Series
  - Lectures - Robert A. Welch Foundation Series
  - Lectures - Rockwell
  - Lectures - Rorschach Memorial Lecture
  - Lectures - Sunday Afternoon
  - Lectures - Technology, Society and Public Policy Series
  - Lectures - Tsanoff Series in the Humanities
  - Lectures - T.W. Leland Jr. in Chemical Engineering
  - Lectures - University Extension
  - Lectures - University Professor Lecture Series
  - Lectures - Urban Group
  - Lectures - Walter and Helen Hall Series
  - Lectures - Wiess School of Natural Sciences
  - Lectures - W.V. Houston Memorial
  - Lecuyer, Maurice Antoine
  - Lee, Benjamin
  - Lee, Cin-Ty
  - Lee, Eva Jean
  - Leebron, David W.
  - Leebron, David W. -- Inauguration (2 Folders)
  - Leeds, J.V.
  - Leeman, William
  - Leeseman, Edith
  - Legacy Society
  - [Rice] Legal History
  - Leighton, Walter
  - Leiper, William Harper
  - Leland, Thomas William, Ph.D.
  - Lentricchia, Frank
  - Lerup, Lars
  - Lesokowitz, John V.
  - Lesser, Zachary
  - LESTER
  - LetterWinner
  - Levander, Alan
  - Levander, Caroline
  - Levi-Civita, Tullio
  - Levin, Donald Norman
  - Levine, Herbert
  - Levy, Eugene
  - Levy, Ferdinand K.
  - Lewis, Carmen
  - Lewis, Edward S.
  - Lewis, Gen. Caroll A.
  - Lewis, Jerry
    See also: Bob Hope
  - Ley Student Center
  - Ley, Wendel D. & Audrey
  - LGBTQ+ at Rice
  - Liang, Edison
    See also: Liberal League of Houston
  - Liberty Bowl 2013
  - Liberal League of Houston
  - Liedtke, J. Hugh
  - Lienhard, John H.
  - [Rice] Light Opera Society
  - Lightpost
  - Lin, Yaun
  - Lindbergh, Charles
  - Lindsay, Cindy
  - Lindsay, D. Michael
  - Linguistics and Semiotics, Dept. of
  - Link, Stephan
  - Literacy and Culture Project
  - Literary Societies
  - Littman, Thomas F.
  - Living Texas Program
  - Livingston, Larry James
  - Llope, Bill
  - Lock-out
    Re. football game; basketball
  - Lockwood, Mason G.
  - Lodal, Jan
  - Loewenheim, Francis (2 folders)
  - Loewenstern, Walter & Karen
  - Logan, Marie-Rose, Dr.
  - [Rice] Logo
  - Lombardi, Cesar Maurice
  - Lone Star Flight Museum
  - Long, Elizabeth
  - Long, Huey P.
  - Long, Kevin
  - Longino, Helen
  - Looney, Dorothy Dawson
  - Lopez, Victor
  - Louis, Andrew
  - Love, Jim
  - Lovett Bench
  - Lovett Chair of Mathematics
  - Lovett, Edgar O.
  - Lovett, Edgar O. - Addresses, 1909-1921
  - Lovett, Edgar O. - Addresses, 1922-1938
  - Lovett, Edgar O. - Addresses, 1939-1945
  - Lovett, Edgar O. - Bethany College Memorial, 1965
  - Lovett, Edgar O. - Death
  - Lovett, Edgar O. - House Lease
  - Lovett, Edgar O. - Portrait
  - Lovett, Edgar O. - Princeton
  - Lovett, Edgar O. - Retirement
  - Lovett, Edgar O. - Statue
  - Lovett, Edgar O. - World Tour
  - Lovett Family
  - Lovett, Henry Malcolm
  - Lovett Hall
  - Lovett, Mrs. E.O. [Mary Ellen Hale]
  - Lovett Society
  - Low, Frank Jones
  - Lowe, Alma Louise
  - Lowenstern, Walter and Karen
  - Lowman, Sara
  - Lowry, Beverly
  - Lucas, Alfred Thomas
  - Luca, Sergiu
  - [Henry W.] Luce Professorship in Engineering Psychology
  - Lucid, Shannon
  - Lummis, Frederick R.
  - Lunar Science Institute
    See also: Photos - Geographic Individual (West Mansion); Drawings Drawer 3
  - Lurie, Susan
  - Lutes, Loren D.
  - Lykes, James Mackay
  - Lyle, W.T.
  - Lynn, Stuart
- Series XIII: M
  - Ma, Jianpeng
  - Ma, Yo-Yo
  - Maas, Michael R.
  - MacArthur, Douglas (General)
  - MacDowell, Carl
  - [Ceremonial] Mace
  - Mackenzie, Donald
  - Mackey, George Whitelaw
  - Mackey, Louis H.
  - MacLane, Gerald R.
  - Macrocosm
  - Madero, Carlos
  - Maegle, Dickey
  - MAES (Study of Mexican American Engineers and Scientists)
  - Magazine- Mens (Rice Publicity)
  - Main Street Boulevard
  - Makdisi, Ussama
  - Managerial Studies
  - Manca, Joseph
  - Mandela, Nelson
  - Mandelbrojt, Szolem
  - Mango, Frank
  - Manned Spacecraft Center
    See also: Johnson Space Center; NASA
  - Manschreck, Clyde L.
  - Manzo, Salvatore
  - Marchiafava, Louis
  - Marcus, George
  - Marenchin, Leslie
  - Marfin, Gary
  - Margrave, John L.
  - Maritime Museum
  - [Rice student] Marriage
  - Marschall, Melissa
  - Marsh, Thad N.
  - Marshall Scholarship
  - Martel College
  - [Marion & Speros] Martel Foundation
  - Martell, Richard
  - Marti, Angel
  - Martin, Greg
  - Martin, Joseph P.
  - Martin, Lanny
  - Martin, Patricia
  - Martin, Randi C.
  - Martin, Robert S.
  - Martin, William C.
  - Martinez, Ray
  - Martinez-Lopez, Sra. E.
  - Martino, Anthony "Little Tony"
  - Martino, Salvatore "Tony"
  - Mascarenhas, Briance
  - [Rice] Masons
  - Masiello, Carrie
  - Massie, Robert K.
  - Massimino, Mike
  - Masterson, Carol and Harris III
  - Masterson Chair in History
  - Masterson Family
  - Masterson, Libbie
  - Masterson, Neill T.
  - Masterson, Peter
  - Masterson, William H. and Orvetta
  - Matchbox Gallery
  - Materials Science and Nanoengineering, Dept. of
  - Mathematical Sciences, Dept. of
  - Mathematics, Dept. of
  - [Rice U. School] Mathematics Project
  - Matherly, Cherly
  - Matriculation Addresses, 1917 - 1950
  - Matriculation Addresses, 1951 - 1979
  - Matriculation Addresses, 1980 -
  - Matsuda, Seiichi
  - Matthews, Charles
  - Matthew, Kathleen S.
  - Matusow, Allen J.
  - Mauzy, Harry
  - Maxfield, Robert
  - May, Bobby
  - May Fete - Clippings, 1920 - 1930
  - May Fete - Clippings, 1931 - 1941
  - May Fete - Programs 1921 - 1941
  - May Fight (Mock May Fete)
  - May Queens
  - McAleese, Mary
  - McAshan Family
  - McAshan, Mrs. Maurice, Jr.
  - McAshan, Samuel M.
  - McAshan, Samuel M. Jr.
  - McAshan, James E.
  - McBride Guy T.
  - McCain, Senator John
  - McCann, S.G.
  - McCants, John Thomas
  - [J. T.] McCants' Notebook - Remembrances of an Early Rice
  - McCardell, William H.
  - McCauley, John
  - McCleary, Thompson
  - McClellan, Rex R.
  - McConnell, Charles
  - McCullough, Helen Louise
  - McDaniel, Caleb
  - McDonald, Ryan
  - McEnany, M.V.
  - McEvilley, Thomas
  - McGhee, Bob
  - McGinty, John M.
  - McGinty, Milton
  - McHugh, Patrick J.
  - McIntire, Larry
  - McIntire, Mary
  - McIntosh, James T.
  - McIntosh Roderick J.
  - McIntosh, Susan Keech
  - McKenzie, C.P.
  - McKillop, A.D.
  - McKinney, Cristy
  - McLean, John
  - McLendon, George
  - McLure, Charles
  - [Carolyn and Fred] McManis Professorship in Philosophy
  - McMaster, Bernie
  - McMurtry, Burt and Deedee
  - McMurtry College
  - McMurtry, Larry
  - McMurtry, Larry - UH Materials Invoice
  - [Burton and Ann] McMurtry Chair in Engineering
  - [Janice and Robert] McNair Hall
  - McNair Hall NEWS
  - McNair, Robert C. & Janice S.
  - McNamara, Robert
  - McNeil, Linda M.
  - McReynolds, Andrew W.
  - McVey, William
    Bust in WRC reading room of William Ward Watkin made by McVey
  - Mead, Margaret
  - Mears, Herbert
  - Mechanical Engineering Building
  - Mechanical Engineering, Department of
  - Mechanical Heart
  - Mecom, John W.
  - Meconi, Honey
  - Media Center
  - Media Relations, Office of
  - Medical Humanities
  - [Rice] Medieval Club
  - Medieval Studies
    See also: O'Brien, Neil J. Conference for Medieval Studies
  - Medina, David D.
  - Meeks, Maymee T.
  - Melanchthon Institute
  - Mellon Fellowship
  - Mellon Grant - April 1988
  - [Andrew W.] Mellon Professorship in the Humanities
  - Melton, Wade
  - [Rice] Memorial Arboretum
  - [Rice] Memorial Center
  - [Rice] Memorial Chapel
  - Menil Collection
  - Menil Foundation
  - Menin Jean-Louis
  - Menorah Society
  - Meredith, Paula
  - Merlo, Antonio
  - Merwin, John E.
  - Metaphors and Symbols Symposium
  - [Rice] Methodist Student Union
  - Metro (Houston Transportation Authority)
  - Meyer, Heinrich
  - Meyer, Leopold
  - Meyers, Charles Jarvis
  - Meyers, James R.
  - Michel, F. Curtis
  - Michener, James
  - Michie, Helena
  - [Rice] Microscope
  - Miele, Angelo
  - Miettinen, Hannu
  - Mikos, Antonios G.
  - Miksch, Walter A.
  - Milburn, Ellsworth
  - [Rice Institute] Military Regulations
  - Military Science, Dept. of
  - Military Service and Training
  - Miller, Clarence A.
  - Miller, Colonel Hugh
  - Miller, Edward M.
  - Miller, Frank William (Jr.)
  - Miller, Jonathan
  - Miller, Mary Emily
  - Miller, Peter M
  - Miller, Robert D.
  - Milligan, W.O.
  - Millis, Eugene
  - Millspaugh, Alvin G.
  - Miner, George R., Jr.
  - Mineral Rights
  - Minority Affairs, Office of
  - Minority Community Affairs Dept.
  - Minority Faculty and Staff at Rice (early period)
  - Minority graduate education
  - Minority graduate program (2 folders)
  - Minter, David
  - "Minute Women" (Post Series)
  - Miranda, Marie L.
  - Missal Leaves
  - Mitchell, Earl Douglas
  - Mitchell, O. Jack
  - Mixon, John
  - Model Science Lab
  - Modern Language Association
  - Mody, Cyrus
  - Mohole Project
  - Moniaci, Steve
  - Montag, Jerry
  - Montgomery, Beverly Anne
  - "[The] Monthly Hoot"
  - Moody Center for the Arts
  - Moody Foundation
  - [Libbi S.] Moody Professorship in English
  - [W.L.] Moody Professorship in Mathematics
  - Moon rock
  - Moon tree planting
  - Moore, Barry
  - Moore, Harvin
  - Moore, Pat H.
  - Moore, Reginald
  - Moore, Stanley C.
  - [Stanley C.] Moore Chair of Engineering
  - Moore, Walter, P. Jr.
  - Moore, Walter, Sr.
  - Moraud, Marcel
  - Morehead, James C., Jr.
  - Morgan, Matt
  - Morgan, O'Dell
  - Morgan, T. Clifton
  - Morin, Robert
  - Morison, Samuel Eliot
  - Morris, Carloss
  - Morris, Harold
  - Morris, Henry C.
  - Morris, Seth Irwin, Jr.
  - Morris, Wesley A.
  - Morrow, Kyle
  - Mosaic
  - Moser, Charles
  - Mott-Smith, L.M.
  - Moussa, Amre
  - Mr. Rice
  - Mubarak, Hosni
  - Mucha, Waclaw
  - [Seeley G.] Mudd Computer Science Laboratory
  - Muench, Nils L.
  - Mugambi, Jesse N. K.
  - Muggeridge, Malcolm
  - Muir, Andrew Forest
  - Mullen, Joseph/Joanna Nazro Mullen
  - Mullen Professorship in Fine Arts
  - Muller, H.J.
  - Multicultural Affairs, Office of
  - Munoz, Chris
  - Murder
  - Murdock, Steve
  - Murdock, William
  - Murphy, Walter D.
  - Murray, Charles
  - Museum of Fine Arts
  - Museum of Funeral History
  - Museum of Printing History
  - Museum of Texas Fishes
  - Music & Performing Arts Center
  - Musiqa
  - Muslim Student Association
  - Mutchler, Gordon S.
- Series XIV: N
  - Nader Raider
    See also: Hill, Kim Quaile
  - Naficy, Hamid
  - Nalle, Joseph
  - Naman, I.A.
  - Name Change (Rice Institute to Rice University)
  - NanoDays
  - NanoKids
  - Nanoscale Science and Technology, Center for
  - Nanotechnology
  - Nanotechnology Enabled Water Treatment System
  - Napier, Albert
  - NASA
  - Natelson, Doug
  - Nathan, William
  - National Academy of Sciences
  - National Accelerator Laboratory
  - National Association for Computing Machinery
  - National Center for Atmospheric Research
  - National Collegiate Athletic Association (NCAA)
  - National Hispanic Institute
  - National Instruments Fellowships
  - National Merit Scholarships
  - National Philanthropy Week
  - National Science Foundation Fellowships
  - National Science Foundation Systems Grants
  - National Space Biomedical Research Institute (NSBRI)
  - Native American Student Association
  - NAU Center for Texas Cultural Heritage
  - NAU Civil War Collection
  - Naval ROTC
  - Neagley, Linda
  - Needham, James C.
  - Neely, Jess
  - Neff, Laura Rice
  - Neidinger, William
  - Neighborhood Centers Inc.
    Alicia Baker founded the group. Corinne Tsanoff was also involved. This is a centennial book describing the group's history.
  - Neighborhoods [near Rice]
    See also: Shadyside; West University Place
  - Nellie (Zoo Elephant)
  - Nelson, Deborah
  - Nelson, William H.
  - Nettleton, Lewis L.
  - Neuroscience, Department of
  - Nevins, Allan
  - New Alumni Picnic
  - Newcomer's Group/Club
  - Newman Club
  - Newman, Jim
  - Newport, John P.
  - News & Publications, Office of
  - Nicandros, Constantine S. "Dino"
  - Nicholas, H.O.
  - Nichols-Rice-Cherry House
  - Nicolaou, K.C.
  - Nielson, Niels, C., Jr.
  - Night of Decadence (NOD)
    See Wiess College Records
  - Night of Innocence (NOI)
    See also: Sid Richardson College Records
  - Ninth College Committee
  - Nirenberg, David
  - Nisbett, Richard
  - NISE Forum
  - Nobel Prize Hoax
  - Noble, Ralph W., Jr.
  - Noble, Stephen T.
  - Nock, Ebba Braathe
  - Nock, Samuel A.
  - Norbeck, Edward
    See also: Center for Research in Social Change and Economic Development
  - Nordlander, Peter
  - Norris, Mary
  - Northrop, J.W.
  - No-Tsu-Oh
  - Noyes, William A.
  - Nuclear power
  - Nuclear reactor
  - Nunn, Stayton
- Series XV: O
  - Obama, Barack
  - O'Bannon, William
  - Oberle, E.J.
  - [Rice Alumni] Obituaries - (through 1996)
  - [Rice Alumni] Obituaries - (1997 - 2000)
  - [Rice Alumni] Obituaries - (2001 - 2004)
  - [Rice Alumni] Obituaries - (2005 - 2008)
  - [Rice Alumni] Obituaries - (2009 - 2013)
  - [Rice Alumni] Obituaries - (2014- )
  - Obituaries- friends and alumni
  - O'Brien, Brian T.
    See also: Space Sciences, Department of
  - O'Brien, Neil J., Conference for Medieval Studies
  - [Ralph S.] O'Connor House
    Earlier records: see President's House / See also: Huff House
  - O'Connor, Ralph
  - O'Dell, Bob (Robert)
  - Oden, Maria
  - Odhiambo, Atieno
  - Off Campus Newsletter
  - O'Grady, Gerald
  - Oil Bowl 1944, 1946, 1947
  - Oil Property
  - O'Keeffe, Richard
  - Old College Inn, Ye
  - Oliver, Covey T.
  - Oliver-Smith, Philip
  - Olivewood Cemetery
  - Olmos, James
  - Olson, John S.
  - [Rice] Olympians
  - O'Malley, Marcia
  - On Campus Day
  - One Hundred (100) Days
  - O'Neill, Haylett, Jr.
  - O'Neil, John
    See also: Fine Arts Department record group and info file
  - OPEN Magazine
  - Openstax
  - Opera Theater
  - Orange Bowl 1947
  - Osburn, Doug
  - Oscars
  - Oshman Engineering Design Kitchen
  - Oshman, M. Kenneth
  - Ostdiek, Barbara
  - Oswald, Larry
  - Other Voices
  - Otremba, Paul
  - [Rice] Outdoors Club
  - Outram, John
  - Outreach
  - Otremba, Paul
  - O-Week
  - Owens, Larry and Leslie
  - Owl
    See also: Sammy (Mascot)
  - Owl Carvings, etc.
  - The Owl Club
  - Owl Days
  - Owl Drawings
  - Owl Literary Society
  - Owl Microfinance
  - Owl News
  - [Rice] Owl Quilt
  - Owl Satellite
  - Owl Sculpture
  - "Owl's-eye View"
  - Owl Weekend
  - OwlBay
  - OWLCON
  - OwlNest
  - OWLNET (student computing system)
- Series XVI: P
  - [Rice] Pacesetter's Club
  - Paddock, Rita
  - Padgett, Jamie
  - Padley, B. Paul
  - Palem, Krishna
  - Palmer, Graham
  - Palmer Memorial Chapel
  - Pan American Round Table
  - Papademetriou, Peter